RG 004:117, Redding Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Redding Probate Court records
1827-1997
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Redding District)
17.25 cubic feet
Record books, 1827-1948; Probate files, 1839-1997.
RG004_117
1933-004, 1987-034, 2012-039, 2012-040
Historical Note
Redding, Fairfield County, Town established in May 1767, Parent Town: Fairfield
The Redding Probate District was constituted May 24, 1839, from the Danbury Probate District. The Redding Probate District merged with the Bethel, Newtown, and Ridgefield Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Northern Fairfield County Probate District which serves the municipalities of Bethel, Newtown, Redding and Ridgefield. Brookfield Probate District presently serves the municipality of Brookfield.
Town of Redding, Probate District chronology:
May 1767 - January 1782, Fairfield District
January 1782 - May 23, 1839, Danbury District
May 24, 1839 - January 4, 2011, Redding District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Northern Fairfield County District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-10, 12-18, 1827-1948. Volume 11 was missing at the probate court and not transferred to the Connecticut State Library. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 18. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1839-1902. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1839-1902 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Samuel L. Clemens will and trust accounts, 1906-1963; Mark Twain Foundation trust accounts, 1986-1997.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered from 1 to 10 and 12 to 18.
Probate files in accessions 1933-004 and 1987-034 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1933-004 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 1987-034.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Redding
Places:
Redding (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2012-039, Record books, 1827-1948, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-5, 7, 10, 12, 14-15, 1839-1919; probate file, 1839-1880; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1933-004 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): November 3, 1933 (1839-1902).
The probate files in accession 1987-034 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on August 7, 1987.
The record books in accession 2012-039, the Samuel L. Clemens will and trust accounts and Mark Twain Foundation trust accounts in accession 2012-040 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on May 16, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1827-1948; 9 cubic feet (17 volumes); 2012-039
  - Records, 1827-1848 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1849-1956 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1856-1863 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1863-1871 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1871-1879 (Volume 5)
  - Orders and decrees, 1871-1882 (Volume 6)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1881-1914 (Volume 7)
  - Bonds, 1881-1914 (Volume 8)
  - Orders and decrees, 1887-1901 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1889-1898 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1902-1906 (Volume 12)
  - Orders and decrees, 1902-1916 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1905-1911 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1912-1917 (Volume 15)
  - Orders and decrees, 1914-1931 (Volume 16)
  - Bonds, 1919-1948 (Volume 17)
  - Records, 1918-1926 (Volume 18)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
- Probate files, 1839-1902; 4.25 cubic feet; 1933-004
  - Abbott - Bartlett (Drawer 1)
  - Bartram - Burr, A. (Drawer 2)
  - Burr, B. - Curtiss (Drawer 3)
  - Darling - Fairchild (Drawer 4)
  - Fanton - Godfrey (Drawer 5)
  - Goodsell - Hawley (Drawer 6)
  - Heddy - Jenkins (Drawer 7)
  - Jennings - Meeker, A. (Drawer 8)
  - Meeker, B. - Perry (Drawer 9)
  - Pickett - Sanford, D. (Drawer 10)
  - Sanford, E. - Shoemaker (Drawer 11)
  - Skidmore - Wallace (Drawer 12)
  - Ward - Zell; Miscellaneous (Drawer 13)
- Inventory Control Book, 1839-1902; T003073
  Index of probate files in accession 1933-004
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1864-1900; 2 cubic feet; 1987-034
  - Abbott - Dayton (Box 1)
  - Denison - Hill, H. (Box 2)
  - Hill, M. - Platt (Box 3)
  - Rowland - Winship (Box 4)
- Probate files, 1906-1997; 2 cubic foot; 2012-040
  - Samuel L. Clemens will and trust accounts, 1906-1963 (Box 1)
  - Mark Twain Foundation trust accounts, 1986-1997 (Box 1)